# Haibao Yu

PhD Student, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Email: yuhaibao94@gmail.com — Phone: +86-130-2110-1122 — Google Scholar — LinkedIn

#### SHORT BIOGRAPHY

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at HKU-MMLAB, The University of Hong Kong, advised by Professor Ping Luo. Additionally, I lead a research team focused on cooperative autonomous driving at the Joint Research Center of Baidu Apollo and AIR-Tsinghua University, collaborating closely with Professor Zaiqing Nie. Previously, I worked as a computer vision researcher for autonomous driving at SenseTime Research. My research encompasses 3D Perception, Motion Forecasting, End-to-End Autonomous Driving, V2X, and Efficient AI. Now, my research interests focus on developing Generative AI and building World Model Simulator for autonomous driving and embodied AI.

## **EDUCATION AND VISITING**

The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China

Ph.D. Student - Computer Science

Research Topics: Autonomous Driving, V2X, Generative AI

Beihang University, Beijing, China

Master - Mathematics and Computational Mathematics

Research Topics: Control System, Differential Equation

Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong, China Visiting Student - High-performance Computing

Sun Yat-Sen University, Guangzhou, China

Bachelor - Mathematics and Applied Mathematics

September 2022 — Present

Advisory: Professor Ping Luo

September 2016 — June 2019 Advisory: Professor Zhikun She

July 2016 — August 2016 Advisory: Professor Xiaowen Chu

September 2012 — June 2016

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Haibao Yu, Wenxian Yang, Jiaru Zhong, Zhenwei Yang, Siqi Fan, Ping Luo, Zaiqing Nie. "End-to-End Autonomous Driving through V2X Cooperation". (Arxiv/Submission, 2024) [Paper] [Code] The first end-to-end framework that seamlessly integrates all key driving modules across diverse views into a unified network.
- Haibao Yu, Yingjuan Tang, Enze Xie, Jilei Mao, Ping Luo, Zaiqing Nie. "Flow-Based Feature Fusion for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative 3D Object Detection". Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 36 (NeurIPS2023)
- Haibao Yu, Wenxian Yang, Hongzhi Ruan, Zhenwei yang, et al. "V2X-Seq: A Large-Scale Sequential Dataset for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative Perception and Forecasting". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2023 (CVPR2023) [Paper] [Dataset] [Code]
- Haibao Yu, Yizhen Luo, Mao Shu, Yiyi Huo, et al. "DAIR-V2X: A Large-Scale Dataset for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative 3D Object Detection". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2022 (CVPR2022) [Paper] [Dataset] [Code]. The first real-world 3D detection dataset for cooperative autonomous driving.
- Haibao Yu\*, Qi Han\*, Jianbo Li, Jianping Shi, Guangliang Cheng, Bin Fan. "Search What You Want: Barrier Penalty NAS for Mixed Precision Quantization". 16th European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV2020)
- Haibao Yu, Tuopu Wen, Guangliang Cheng, Jiankai Sun, Qi Han, Jianping Shi. "Low-bit Quantization Needs Good Distribution". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops (CVPRW2020)
- Siqi Fan, Haibao Yu, Wenxian Yang, Jirui Yuan, Zaiqing Nie. "Quest: Query Stream for Vehicle-Infrastructure Cooperative Perception". 2024 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automatio (ICRA2024)
- Hongzhi Ruan, Haibao Yu, Wenxian Yang, Siqi Fan, Yingjuan Tang, Zaiqing Nie. "Learning Cooperative Trajectory Representations for Motion Forecasting". (Arxiv/Submission, 2024)
- Yao Mu, Junting Chen, Qinglong Zhang, Shoufa Chen, Qiaojun Yu, Chongjian Ge, Runjian Chen, Zhixuan Liang, Mengkang Hu, Chaofan Tao, Peize Sun, Haibao Yu, et al. "RoboCodeX: Multimodal Code Generation for Robotic

<sup>\*</sup> denotes equal contribution.

Behavior Synthesis". International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML2024)

- Ruiyang Hao\*, Siqi Fan\*, Yingru Dai, Zhenlin Zhang, Chenxi Li, Yuntian Wang, **Haibao Yu**, et al. "Roooper: A Real-World Large-Scale Dataset for Roadside Cooperative Perception". The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2024 (CVPR2024)
- Tao Yang, Zhezhi He, Tengchuan Kou, Qingzheng Li, Qi Han, Haibao Yu, Fangxin Liu, Yun Liang, Li Jiang. "A
  Winograd-based CNN Accelerator with A Fine-grained Regular Sparsity Pattern and Mixed Precision Quantization".
  ACM Transactions on Reconfigurable Technology and Systems (TRETS, 2021)

# WORK EXPERIENCES: FULL TIME/PART TIME

#### Institute of AI Industry Research (AIR), Tsinghua University

Beijing, China

Work Experience: I am working at the Joint Research Center of AIR & Baidu Apollo, collaborating with Professor Zaiqing Nie. I lead a research team comprising 5-10 engineers and interns, focused on autonomous driving and V2X.

• Research Assistant/Intern

September 2022 — Present

• Research Engineer

May 2021 — August 2022

## Projects & Research Results

- Releasing a series of real-world datasets: DAIR-V2X, V2X-Seq, DAIR-RCooper
- Hosing challenges and workshop: 3D Object Detection Challenge, Coop-Intelligence Workshop

### Department of Autonomous Driving, SenseTime

Beijing, China

Work Experience: I worked closely with Dr. Jianping Shi and Dr. Guangliang Cheng. I led an R&D team focused on deep learning model compression and deployment for autonomous driving, and participated in several mass production projects.

• Computer Vision Researcher

April 2019 — May 2021

• Computer Vision Research Intern

March 2018 — March 2019

#### Projects & Research Results

- Model Compression and Acceleration: 4-bit & 8-bit quantization framework, sparse acceleration framework
- Model Deployment for Different Chips: FPGA, Ambarella, Nvidia, Qualcomm, et al.
- Autonomous Driving Mass Production: L0 ADAS for Hozon Auto, L2 ADAS for GAC Group

### **HONORS** and **AWARDS**

| • Research Innovation Award, SenseTime (20 applied, only 3 were awarded.)                      | 2020 |
|--|------|
| • National Scholarship, Beihang University   | 2018 |
| • President's Scholarship, Beihang University  | 2017 |
| • Innovation and Entrepreneurship Scholarship, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology | 2017 |
| • 4th place winner of JD X Robot Challenge, Jingdong (prize: 20,000 RMB)                       | 2017 |
| National Encouragement Scholarship, Sun Yat-sen University                                     | 2014 |

#### ACADEMIC SERVICES

- Academic Activities:
  - Primary Organizer of Workshop on Cooperative Intelligence for Autonomous Driving and Robotics, ECCV2024
  - Program Committe of Wearable Intelligence for Healthcare Robotics Workshop, ICRA2024
- Conference Reviewer:
  - CVPR(2023, 2024), ICCV(2023), ECCV(2022, 2024)
- Journal Reviewer:
  - IEEE Internet of Things Journal
  - IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology